-- Usagi Drop Episode 03 --
Those of you with Type B, listen carefully.
Should this be left alone, it will surely threaten the fabric of your life!
Turn it off!
Turn off that sick show!
It wasn't that scary.
Shall we take a bath?
Will I die too?
Huh?
What do you mean? You're only six years old.
Whoops.
Presented by:
Taka Fansubs
See you.
If I don't find a new daycare soon, we'll be in trouble.
You'd think a corporation that employs smart people would think to have a daycare itself.
But what kind of country has that?
Oh, Kawachi-san!
Hey.
Do you have a girlfriend, Kawachi-san?
What?
You've been rushing home early lately.
No, I don't have one.
You used to always take the last train of the day.
Our sales were out of this world last year, thanks to you.
But, if you keep this up...
Those sales figures weren't born out of willpower or determination.
It was just a coincidence.
My name means "super lucky," after all.
Kawachi-san!
Wait!
Here, I'll take some.
Oh, thank you.
Fourth floor, right?
Yeah. How are things here?
This year's been rough.
In fact, he was just stacking the pressure on me.
I think I'm going bald from the stress.
It's not easy surpassing your own record, is it?
So, Gotou-san, do you really have a kid?
Don't judge me just because I'm short!
No, it's just you're so thin, I was
wondering if you really had a baby.
I can't remember, either!
He's already two.
Thanks, I'll take them now.
I can carry them.
It's fine, I got it.
Okay.
Take care!
She's energetic, as always.
I wish she was still in sales.
She was here years before me,
but during her pregnancy,
she requested to be demoted so she could get home at the same time every day.
Other employees would always gossip about her.
What?! For how long?
I'm not really sure yet.
Rin-chan, huh?
She's been wetting the bed recently.
It looks like it really upsets her.
Maybe it's psychological.
Still, kids really do sweat an astonishing amount.
But since they can't sweat much during autumn and winter,
they have to pee a lot more to compensate.
Oh yeah, I remember hearing that as a kid.
"Make sure you pee before going to bed."
Her mother must have had a good reason to leave her.
I wish I could ask her some things.
I guess having a mother is really important, isn't it?
Men shouldn't give in so easily!
Do your best!
What'd you do today?
I read picture books and had staring contests...
Did you have fun?
What's she doing?
Rin, I'll make dinner right away.
The moon's fading away.
Maternity and Child
Care Handbook
Kaga Souichi
Yoshii Masako
Rin
Hello?
So, how's it going?
I'm doing fine.
I wasn't asking about you.
Oh, she's fine too.
Hold on, I thought you didn't want to get involved with her?
I have to get involved. You're watching over her, after all.
I'm gonna try to find Rin's mom this weekend, so I'll be on your side of town.
Okay. Call me when you're at the station.
Make sure you dress her properly for the cold!
Right. I'll call Haruko too.
Our two kids seem to get along well.
We passed another car!
Seems like you're having fun.
Yup!
We're here.
Welcome home.
It's good to see you, Rin-chan!
Hey!
I'm sorry, I don't have anything a child would like.
She likes things adults do anyway. Isn't that right?
Finished already?
Yeah.
Don't complain if you get hungry again.
I'm full.
I'm sorry I didn't finish my plate.
I'm home! Sorry I'm late.
What a drag! What's with that family?!
Brother, you really took this girl in?!
Yeah.
And here's the forecast.
It will be warm and sunny across the nation today.
Temperatures will be about two degrees higher than usual for this time of year.
I'm just going to the bathroom.
Now then, on to tomorrow's forecast.
I'm using the bathroom!
I can't go if you're right outside.
Is she always like this?
No, she's actually pretty chatty at home.
She even acted like going on the train was some kind of trip.
But, all the adults here last time were really tense around her.
What did we do?!
Idiot. If adults are in a bad mood, kids think they're angry at them.
He's right. You two were like that too.
See! You used to be exactly like her!
But Rin's smarter than you were!
Shut it, baldie!
Rin-chan, you like cat's cradle, don't you?
Go on, give an answer.
Yeah.
This is for you.
It's so pretty.
Now watch your Auntie do it, okay?
I think you mean "Grandma," don't you?
You don't look old enough to be my grandma!
Oh my! What a nice girl!
Her basis for what counts as old is lopsided, that's all.
Now watch me do it!
Huh? Did I make a mistake?
Huh?
Did you want to do a four-step ladder?
Wow!
Two-step ladder.
Airplane.
Slide.
Diamond.
You're amazing!
Wow.
It's easy with this string.
Did you make this?
Yes, I knitted it from thin wool.
Its weight balance is much better than simply making loops out of the wool.
Hold on!
Since she's good with her hands,
maybe she can play with beanbags!
You hang it on your pinky.
Like this?
Yeah!
One went up, two came down...
What on earth is going on in here?!
What are you talking about?
Coming!
Who is it?
Probably Haruko-san.
Rin-chan!
These are pretty! What are they called?
Beanbags.
Thanks for coming.
Not at all.
You're really doing great, raising a child and working at the same time.
My husband doesn't help out at home at all.
Are you heading over to Grandpa's house?
Yeah, I figured I might find
something there about Rin's mom.
Yeah, maybe.
Having a mother is important, after all.
That's strange.
You should've at least left a will behind, Grandpa.
Weren't you worried about what would happen to Rin?
A modem?
I'm back.
What's with that look?!
I got it done the same as Reina-chan!
Did you get new clothes too?
They're Kazumi's.
Did you say Kazumi?
Mom, you can't dress her up in old-fashioned clothes like that!
But look how nice she looks in them!
Well, I guess.
They only look good because of her figure.
It sure brings back memories.
Any luck at Grandpa's house?
Nope, none.
I see.
Still, I think it's best not to rush
to press the issue with Rin-chan.
I can tell you're trying hard.
I'm not sure whether we ever told you or not,
but your mother started working after you were born.
Huh? She wasn't always a housewife?
She pushed herself too far when pregnant with Kazumi, and had to be hospitalized for a while.
When she went back to work, they had removed her position completely.
She felt really down after that.
And because Kazumi was so tiny when she was born,
your mother would leave work early and come home to look after you two.
What about Kazumi?
Your mother made doting on Kazumi her top priority,
making her the arrogant woman she is today.
Will you be okay? Do you want Dad to take you?
It's fine. We'll just make it if we walk.
Can we come again?
She wants to know if she can come again.
I'll be waiting for you, so come any time you want.
See you.
What are you talking about?!
I just thought it'd be nice to have a grandchild!
I'd take care of it!
I can't work and raise a child at the same time!
That's when women get left behind!
Besides, I still want to fit into a swimsuit and go out drinking!
Rin, did Grandpa have a computer?
Do you know what that is?
Yeah.
Did Grandpa use one?
No, the maid did.
He had a maid?
Her name was Masako-san.
Maternity and Child
Care Handbook
Kaga Souichi
Yoshii Masako
Rin
What was she like?
I can't really remember.
I hate her.
She was always angry at me. She hated me.
I forgot about her because she scared me.
I see.
I know it's a little late to be saying this,
but it really is hard working while raising a kid, isn't it?
You said it. It sure keeps us busy.
Gotou-san, have you ever thought you sacrificed a lot to raise your child?
Like when I asked to be demoted?
I'm sorry, I know this must sound rude...
Well, back then I thought it was the best choice,
and things turned out alright in the end.
Even if I have sacrificed myself, it's not something I'd want to talk about.
Words carry power within them.
You know, like the soul of language.
Or is that too abstract?
No, I completely understand what you mean!
Please give me more advice about raising a child!
Kawachi-kun, your child's older than mine!
You're my senior in that regard. You should advise me!
Rin, it's okay to wake me up.
But it's just sweat!
I don't care if it's sweat or not.
Did you have a scary dream?
What does dying feel like?
Daikichi, are you going to die before I do?
Her sadness over Grandpa's death...
Her worry over what'll happen if I die too...
Her fear of dying herself...
She can't deal with all those things individually, so she lets them pile up inside of her.
Everything will be fine until you're a young lady.
When's that?
I mean, everything will be fine until you're a grown-up woman!
I won't die until then!
I promise.
Okay.
And don't worry about wetting the bed.
It'll stop if you go to the bathroom before sleeping.
But the bathroom's scary!
Then I'll go with you at night.
And even if you still wet the bed, all we have to do is change your pants.
You won't be mad?
I won't be mad. Nor will I laugh about it.
Okay.
So, what'd you want to talk about?
I'm really sorry for suddenly bringing this up, Hidaka-san.
I know this is really unexpected,
but could you please transfer me to a section with no overtime?
What? Are you serious, Kawachi?
As serious as it gets!
I see, so that's why.
In my opinion, this'll be a real loss for us.
But, I have a child as well.
I'll try to convince the section head to grant your request.
I'm truly sorry. Thank you for understanding.
Still, your subordinates won't be too happy.
I can't accept that!
Why do you have to do it, Kawachi-san?!
Can't you ask one of your relatives?
I guess I shouldn't tell him that I chose to watch over her.
Besides, aren't there daycares that stay open until late at night?
I don't want to work for someone other than you!
Look, I know this is really sudden,
but managers and the like transfer suddenly all the time!
Stop making a big deal out of it!
Still, I'm really sorry.
Even if I'm not there, things will
eventually settle down in my section.
They'll move people around.
Otherwise something would be off with the company.
But I can't keep making Rin go on like this.
I'm sure I'm doing the right thing.
Probably...
Is it done?
Yeah. Is this enough rice for you?
Yeah!
Admissions Guide
Towel, lunch box, slippers, toothbrush, cup...
With your name on them all.
Futon?!
Oh, that's only for babies.
Let's go!
Hurry up, Daikichi!
I can't say I'm not sacrificing anything
right now, without it sounding like a lie,
but I hope one day I'll be able to say it out loud.
Rin, what is this you've got all over your towel and lunch box?
That dog with huge ears.
It's not a dog!
It's a lop-ear!
Lop-what? What's that?
It's a rabbit!
Huh? So it's not a dog with spots?
Mine!
Rin, it's bathroom time.
I already went.
Oh.